Guide to the Ellen Van Volkenburg and Maurice Browne papers vvb
University of Michigan Library (Special Collections Research Center)
- Correspondence
  - Name File
    - Robertson, Donald (Box 10)
    - Robertson, Eileen Arbuthnot (Box 10)
    - Robeson, Eslanda (Box 10)
    - Robeson, Paul (Box 10)
    - Robson, Flora (Box 10)
    - Roeder, Ralph (Box 10)
    - Rogers, Rosemary (Box 10)
    - Rorke, Kate (Box 10)
    - Rosmer, Milton (Box 10)
    - Rosenfeld, Sybil Marion (Box 10)
    - Ross, Nancy Wilson
      - Outgoing correspondence, 1937-1971; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Ana, 1963 (Box 10)
    - Roth, Leonard (Box 10)
    - Rothkowitz, Marcus (Box 10)
    - Routh, Harold Victor (Box 10)
    - Rowntree, Benjamin Seebhom (Box 10)
    - Rubinstein, Harold Frederick (Box 10)
    - Rutherford, Kathleen E. (Box 10)
    - St. Denis, Michel (Box 10)
    - Saintsbury, Harry Arthur (Box 10)
    - Sanders, Dorothy (Box 10)
    - Sandor, Marian N. (Box 10)
    - Sarg, Tony (Box 10)
    - Sargent, Franklin H. (Box 10)
    - Saroyan, William (Box 10)
    - Sayers, Dorothy Leigh
      - Outgoing correspondence
        - Browne, Maurice, 1936-1947 (Box 10)
        - Morris, Marjorie, 1937 (Box 10)
    - Sayler, Oliver Martin (Box 10)
    - Saylor, Oliver
      - Incoming correspondence, 1930-1949 (Box 10)
      - Outgoing correspondence
        - Browne, Maurice, 1931-1935 (Box 10)
        - Funke, Lewis, 1949 (Box 10)
    - Sax, Carol M. (Box 10)
    - Scaife, Gillian (Box 10)
    - Schaeffer, William E. (Box 10)
    - Schevill, Ferdinand (Box 10)
    - Schick, Hedi (Box 10)
    - Schindler, Pauline G. (Box 10)
    - Schlesinger, Kathleen (Box 10)
    - Scofield, Paul (Box 10)
    - Scott, Cyril Meir (Box 10)
    - Scott-Gatty, Alexander (Box 10)
    - Sen, Gertrude (Emerson) (Box 10)
    - Sewell, Emma (Box 10)
    - Sharp, Cecil James (Box 10)
    - Shaw, George Bernard
      - Outgoing correspondence
        - Browne, Maurice, 1914-1939 (Box 10)
        - Browne, J. A., 1924 (Box 10)
    - Shaw, Glen Byam (Box 10)
    - Shaw, Howard Van Doren (Box 10)
    - Sheldon, Edward Brewster (Box 10)
    - Sheldon, William (Box 10)
      Student.
    - Sheringham, George (Box 10)
    - Sherriff, Robert Cedric (Box 10)
    - Sherwood, Lydia (Box 10)
    - Sherwood, Margaret (Box 10)
    - Sherwood, Robert Emmet (Box 10)
    - Shove, John (Box 10)
    - Sidwell, Frances H. (Box 10)
    - Sill, Louise Morgan (Smith) (Box 10)
    - Sillman, Leonard Dexter (Box 10)
    - Sim, Alastair (Box 10)
    - Simonson, Lee (Box 10)
    - Simpson, Lilian Eva (Brown) (Box 10)
    - Sims, E. Florence (Wykes) (Box 10)
    - Sinclair, Upton Bell (Box 10)
    - Sinclair, Walter (Box 10)
    - Smallwood, Stella (Box 10)
    - Smedmore, Rodney (Box 10)
    - Smith, Mollie (Box 10)
    - Sobieniowski, Floryan (Box 10)
    - Soelberg, Louise (Box 10)
    - Sofaer, Abraham (Box 10)
    - Somerset, Dorothy (Box 10)
    - Sothern, Edward Hugh (Box 10)
    - Speaight, Robert (Box 10)
    - Spencer, Marian (Box 10)
    - Spencer, Mowbray (Box 10)
    - Springer, Ada E. (Box 10)
    - Squire, Sir John Collings (Box 10)
    - Staniland, Mair (Box 10)
    - Stanislavskiĭ, Konstantin Sergeevich (Box 10)
    - Stark, Freya (Box 10)
    - Stedman, Jeannette (Box 10)
    - Steloff, Frances (Box 10)
    - Stephens, James (Box 10)
    - Stern, Ernest Julian (Box 10)
    - Stevens, Harold Charles Gilbert (Box 10)
    - Stewart, R. C. (Rolland Clifford)
      - Correspondence
        - Incoming correspondence, 2 folders (Box 10)
        - Outgoing correspondence
          - Van Volkenburg, Ellen, 1955-1958; 3 folders (Box 10)
          - Underwood, Molly (Box 10)
        - Henry Sotheran, Ltd. (Box 10)
          Incoming and outgoing correspondence.
      - Ellen Van Volkenburg Browne biographical data (Box 10)
    - Stickney, Dorothy (Box 10)
    - Stirling, Michael (Box 10)
    - Stocker, Richard Dimsdale (Box 10)
    - Stormont, Elsie (Box 10)
    - Storrs, Sir Ronald (Box 10)
    - Straight, Beatrice, 1934-1970 (Box 10)
    - Straight, Michael Whitney (Box 10)
    - Straight, Whitney (Box 10)
    - Straus, Bertram Stuart (Box 10)
    - Straus, Ralph (Box 10)
    - Stringer, Arthur John Arbuthnott (Box 10)
    - Swing, Raymond (Box 10)
    - Symons, Arthur (Box 10)
    - Symons, Rhoda (Box 10)
    - Synge, Edward (Box 10)
    - Széchényi, Gladys (Vanderbilt), countess (Box 10)
    - Tait, J. N. (Box 10)
    - Tandy, Jessica (Box 10)
    - Taube, Margaret Eaton (Box 10)
    - Taylor, A. E. (Box 10)
    - Taylor, Frederick Irving (Box 10)
    - Tearle, Sir Godfrey (Box 10)
    - Temple, Joan (Box 10)
    - Tennant, Constance (Box 10)
    - Terriss, Ellaline (Box 10)
    - Thomas, Edna V. V. (Box 10)
    - Thomas, Emily (Box 10)
    - Thomson, Alice (Box 10)
    - Thorndike, Dame Sybil (Box 11)
    - Tietjens, Eunice (Hammond) (Box 11)
    - Tilley, Erma S. (Box 11)
    - Tobey, Mark (Box 11)
    - Townsend, Jo (Box 11)
    - Trask, Julia S. (Box 11)
    - Trites, William Budd (Box 11)
    - Tucker, Sophie (Box 11)
    - Turner, John Hastings (Box 11)
    - Twitchell, Virginia (Box 11)
    - Tyas, Bessie (Box 11)
    - Tyler, Carolyn D. (Box 11)
    - Underwood, Molly, 1947 (Box 11)
    - Updike, Estelle R. (Box 11)
    - Urmey, Edythe Beatrice (Box 11)
    - Uttridge, George C. (Box 11)
    - Vail, Patty (Box 11)
    - Vanbrugh, Dame Irene (Box 11)
    - Vanbrugh, Violet August Mary (Box 11)
    - Vandenberg, Hazel (Whittaker) (Box 11)
    - Van der Post, Laurens (Box 11)
    - Van Slyke, Beren (Box 11)
    - Van Volkenburg, Juliet (Cooper), 1929 and undated (Box 11)
      To F. A. B. and Ellen Van Volkenburg.
    - Vedder, Simon Harmon (Box 11)
    - Veevers, Vivien (Box 11)
    - Vickers, Squire J. (Box 11)
    - Volt, Herman (Box 11)
    - Wagenknecht, Edward Charles
      - Outgoing correspondence, ca. 1955-1968 (Box 11)
      - Writings, 1934 (Box 11)
        Review and typescript (carbon copy).
    - Waldman, Milton (Box 11)
    - Walker, Dugald Stewart (Box 11)
    - Wallace, Edgar (Box 11)
    - Walsh, Richard John (Box 11)
    - Walsy?, Abb__? (Box 11)
    - Walter, Wilfried (Box 11)
    - Walters, Anne (Box 11)
    - Walters, John Cuming (Box 11)
    - Wanamaker, Sam (Box 11)
    - Ward, Richard Heron (Box 11)
    - Watson, Dudley Crafts (Box 11)
    - Watson, Mary Spencer (Box 11)
    - Watson, Stuart (Box 11)
    - Watts, Diana (Mrs. Roger Watts) (Box 11)
    - West, Irene (Box 11)
    - Wettergren, Karl Erik Wilhelm Frederik (Box 11)
    - Whale, James (Box 11)
    - Wheeler, Gladys (Box 11)
    - Wheeler, Penelope (Box 11)
    - Whelen, Frederick (Box 11)
    - Whitaker, Florence A. (Box 11)
    - White, Alice T. (Box 11)
    - Whiteside, Abby (Box 11)
    - Whitling, Townsend (Box 11)
    - Whitworth, Phyllis (Box 11)
    - Widtsoe, John Andreas (Box 11)
    - Wigman, Mary (Box 11)
    - Wild, Marjorie (Box 11)
    - Wilfred, Thomas (Box 11)
    - Wilkinson, Anne (Box 11)
    - Wilkinson, Ellen Cicely (Box 11)
    - Wilkinson, Frances Gregg (Box 11)
    - Wilkinson, Louis Umfreville (Box 11)
    - Williams, E. Harcourt (Box 11)
    - Wilson, John Dover (Box 11)
    - Wilstach, John (Box 11)
    - Winston, Harold (Box 11)
    - Winter, George (Box 11)
    - Wiseman, A. H. (Box 11)
    - Wolff, Keinert S. (Box 11)
    - Wood Family
      - Field, Sara Bard
        - Incoming correspondence
          - Browne, Maurice (Box 11)
          - Van Volkenburg, Ellen (Box 11)
        - Outgoing correspondence
          - Browne, Maurice (Box 11)
          - Van Volkenburg, Ellen (Box 11)
        - Poems (Box 11)
      - Shyott, Katherine Field (Box 11)
      - Wood, Charles Erskine Scott
        - Incoming correspondence
          - Beall, Upton Beall (Box 11)
          - Browne, Maurice (Box 11)
          - Sinclair, Upton (Box 11)
          - Van Volkenburg, Ellen (Box 11)
        - Outgoing Correspondence
          - Browne, Maurice (Box 11)
          - Greene, Alex (Box 11)
          - Van Volkenburg, Ellen, 2 folders (Box 11)
        - Inscriptions (Box 11)
        - Works
          - Bacchus (Box 11)
          - Circe, 6 folders (Box 11)
          - Odysseus (Box 11)
          - On the Heights (Box 11)
          - Poems (Box 11)
        - Ana (Box 11)
    - Wood, Georgie (Box 11)
    - Wood, Mary Whistler (Box 11)
    - Wright, Huntley (Box 11)
    - Wyllie, Jim W. (Box 11)
    - Wyngate, Valérie (Box 11)
    - Wynyard, Diana (Box 11)
    - Yeats-Brown, Francis Charles Claypon (Box 11)
    - Young, Ella (Box 11)
    - Young, Stark (Box 11)
    - Yurka, Blanche (Box 11)
    - Zimmern, Sir Alfred Eckhard (Box 11)
- Writings
  - Maurice Browne writings
    - Maurice Browne autobiography: Too Late to Lament
      - "Autobiog" (Box 12)
      - Too Late to Lament Book One: "Second Copy" (Box 12)
        Typescript with autograph revisions.
      - Too Late to Lament Book Two: "Part II of Original Autobiography (ca. 1937)" (Box 12)
        Typescript (carbon copy) with autograph revisions.
      - Too Late to Lament Book Two: "Second Copy" (Box 12)
      - Too Late to Lament Book Three manuscript (Box 12)
        Four red exercise books, holograph.
      - Too Late to Lament Book Three: "Second Copy" (Box 12)
      - Too Late to Lament Book Four, Epilogue, Notes, and Acknowledgment (Box 12)
      - Too Late to Lament Book Four typescript (Box 12)
        With autograph notes.
      - Too Late to Lament chapter headings (Box 12)
      - Too Late to Lament chapters ten-twelve (Box 12)
      - Too Late to Lament correspondence (Box 12)
        For Volume 2.
      - Too Late to Lament discarded forwards (Box 12)
      - Too Late to Lament discards
        - From Prologue (Box 12)
          Typescript with autograph annotations.
        - From Book Three (Box 12)
        - From Book Four (Box 12)
        - From Epilogue (Box 12)
        - General (Box 12)
      - Too Late to Lament Epilogue (Box 12)
      - Too Late to Lament: "Extracts from Early Notebooks, etc." (Box 12)
      - Too Late to Lament "Final Corrections" notebook, ca. 1948-1954 (Box 12)
      - Too Late to Lament leaves (Box 12)
        Leaves removed from the original manuscript of Book Three of Maurice Browne's autobiography.
      - Too Late to Lament letters, 1938-1953 (Box 12)
        Regarding Maurice Browne's autobiography.
      - Too Late to Lament material for volume 2, 2 folders (Box 12)
      - "My Life, Confession, and Faith (Provisional Title Only)" (Box 12)
      - Too Late to Lament notes (Box 12)
      - "Pall Mall" (Box 12)
        Reprint.
      - "Search" (Box 12)
      - "Suggested Outline for an Autobiography" (Box 12)
      - "Tunisian Treasure Trove" (Box 12)
    - Maurice Browne plays
      - The Death of Adam: "First draft of opening of, and notes for...", ca. 1916 (Box 12)
      - Dr. Job excisions (Box 12)
        Holographs and typescripts.
      - Dr. Job: A Mystery Play in Two Parts typescript, ca. 1945-1947 (Box 12)
        Carbon copy) with holograph revisions.
      - Dr. Job: A Play in Two Parts typescript: "B's copy", [1945] (Box 12)
      - God and Miss Sippy
        - God and Miss Sippy: A Comedy typescript, ca. 1923-1947 (Box 13)
          With holograph revisions.
        - The Strange Case of God and Miss Sippy: An Irresponsible Comedy typescript, 1923-1924 (Box 13)
          Original typescript, per Maurice Browne. With holograph revisions.
      - Jesus of Nazareth: A Tragedy: "First draft of the opening of...", ca. 1912 (Box 13)
      - The King of the Jews: A Passion Play
        - The King of the Jews: "Revised and in Part Rewritten: Halcyon", 1915 (Box 13)
          Typescript with holograph revisions. Accompanied by excisions and a typescript carbon copy of notes.
        - The King of the Jews: "Ms., Programmes, Letters, etc.", 1915-1916 and undated (Box 13)
          Holograph manuscripts and related documents, including an annotated envelope for The Mother of Gregory.
        - The King of the Jews typescript (Box 13)
          With holograph corrections. Prepared for inclusion in "Collected Plays".
        - The King of the Jews: negative-image photocopies of book pages, 1916 (Box 13)
        - The King of the Jews: "Revised and in Part Rewritten: Halcyon, Feb. 7, 1945", 1915 (Box 13)
          Carbon copy.
        - The King of the Jews: "Father Weed's Copy", 1958-1969 (Box 13)
          "Copy No. 2". Typescript (carbon copy).
        - The King of the Jews typescript (carbon copy) (Box 13)
          Inscription: "Return to: Ellen Van Volkenburg Browne, Barbizon Plaza Hotel, New York, N.Y."
        - The King of the Jews typescript (1925 revision) (Box 13)
          Revision of original manuscript (1915). Carbon copy; cover marked "#2".
        - The King of the Jews typescript and correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 13)
        - The King of the Jews miscellany, 1916-1943 and undated (Box 13)
      - Marnath: A Tragedy manuscript, 1902 (Box 13)
      - The Mother of Gregory: A Ballad Play
        - The Mother of Gregory typescript (Box 13)
        - The Mother of Gregory typescript (Box 13)
          Carbon copy. Includes holograph revisions.
        - The Mother of Gregory typescript (Box 13)
          Carbon copy. Accompanied by 8 pages of excisions.
        - The Mother of Gregory typescript (Box 13)
          Carbon copy. Includes holograph revisions. Inscription: "Please return to: Maurice Browne, Quarrenden, Tothes, Devon, England".
        - The Mother of Gregory typescript, 1934 (Box 13)
          Carbon copy. Inscription: "This version–1934–is superseded by that included in my 'Collected Plays' -M.B., 1948".
        - The Mother of Gregory autograph, typescript, and carbon copy, ca. 1922-1923 (Box 13)
        - The Mother of Gregory holograph, undated (Box 13)
        - The Mother of Gregory empty note cover, undated (Box 13)
      - Mrs. Denham's Sun: A Play: "First draft of beginning of...", ca. 1913-1914? (Box 13)
      - Orvieto: A Play in One Act in Verse
        Also known as In Thine High Places.
        - Orvieto typescript, 1911 (Box 13)
          Carbon copy. Includes autograph revisions.
        - "In Thin and High Places" manuscript (Box 13)
          Holograph. Written in a grey notebook.
        - In Thine High Places: A Poetic Drama in One Act manuscript, ca. 1911 (Box 13)
      - These Mortals: A Very Tragical Comedy manuscript, ca. 1912 (Box 13)
        Holograph in black notebook.
      - Tomorrow's Sun / The Wife of William Flavy / What Men Call Honour
        - Tomorrow's Sun
          - Tomorrow's Sun progams and related materials, 1942 and undated (Box 13)
          - Tomorrow's Sun typescript, 1942 (Box 13)
            Molly's copy.
          - Tomorrow's Sun ribbon copy, 1942 (Box 13)
            Ellen Van Volkenburg's Copy (#1).
          - Tomorrow's Sun carbon copy, 1942 (Box 13)
            Ellen Van Volkenburg's copy (#2).
          - Tomorrow's Sun try-out prompt copy, 1942 (Box 13)
          - Tomorrow's Sun typescript, ca. 1954 (Box 13)
            "Not-corrected by author's copy." B's copy.
        - The Wife of William Flavy
          - The Wife of William Flavy: A Tale typescript, 1936 (Box 13)
          - The Wife of William Flavy: A Tale typescript, 1934 (Box 13)
            Joan Antill Copy.
          - The Wife of William Flavy: A Tale typescript, 1928 (Box 13)
            Bound typescript inscribed to "Dorothy and Leonard". Working copy.
          - The Wife of William Flavy: A Tragedy typescript, undated (Box 13)
            With a note regarding At the Bells, 1957.
          - The Wife of William Flavy: A Tragedy autograph manuscript, 1954; 2 Volumes (Box 13)
            Started "5.xii.1954".
          - The Wife of William Flavy typescript, ca. 1923-1928 (Box 13)
            Bound typescript, "apparently first version". Working copy.
          - The Wife of William Flavy typescript, ca. 1923-1928 (Box 13)
            First or second version?
          - The Wife of William Flavy autograph manuscript, 1924; 2 Volumes (Box 14)
            Second draft.
          - "Flavy", ca. 1928 (Box 14)
            Autograph manuscript. Created prior to first publication.
          - The Wife of William Flavy typescripts, undated (Box 14)
            Deleted scenes.
      - Wings over Europe
        By Robert Nichols and Maurice Browne.
        - Wings over Europe character sketches (Box 14)
        - Wings over Europe memorabilia (Box 14)
        - Wings over Europe typescript, ca. 1928 (Box 14)
          Includes autograph revisions.
        - Wings over Europe materials (Box 14)
          Items from the Wings over Europe prompt copy, removed by Special Collections staff.
        - The Part of Evelyn Arthur typescript (Box 14)
          Includes autograph notations.
        - Wings over Europe typescript (Box 14)
          Carbon copy with autograph revisions. Accompanied by Theatre Guild program and typescript notation by A. N. Whitehead.
        - Wings over Europe: "Copy showing ms. corrections by R. N. and M. B." (Box 14)
          Typescript with autgraph revisions.
        - Wings over Europe: "Rough prompt copy" (Box 14)
      - Yseult of Ireland: A Ballad Play manuscript, ca. 1923-1925 (Box 14)
      - Yseult of Ireland: A Tale manuscript, ca. 1926 (Box 14)
      - Untitled typescript, 1936 (Box 14)
        "Based on 'Guilty Soul' by Robert Nichols." Includes holograph revisions.
    - Maurice Browne prose
      - "Alternative Plans for Publishing My Verse and Plays" (Box 14)
      - Bare Boards: A Book of Memories and Essays Mainly about the Theatre
        - Bare Boards: A Book of Memories and Essays Mainly about the Theatre typescripts, undated (Box 14)
          Includes autograph revisions. Seemingly the copy on which the working copy is based.
        - Bare Boards: A Book of Memories and Essays Mainly about the Theatre: "Working Copy", 1951 (Box 14)
      - Bare Boards: A Little Book of Search Mainly in the Theatre typescript, June 26, 1948 (Box 14)
      - Chicago Memories and the Trojan Women, undated (Box 14)
      - "Comments on a Review of Mr. Faust" (Box 14)
      - "Comments on Stringberg's Creditors", 1927 (Box 14)
      - Conventional Essays: A Réchauffé of Other Men's Views, by a Grub Street Hack", 1906 (Box 14)
      - Eastern Silhouettes: 1904-1905 typescript, ca. 1904-1936 (Box 14)
        Includes autograph revisions and photographs.
      - Eastern Silhouettes frontispiece, ca. 1913 (Box 14)
      - The Heart to Endure, 1918-1925 (Box 14)
      - Indian Diary
        - Indian Diary general materials, 2 folders (Box 14)
        - "Pages from an Indian Diary" (Box 14)
        - Indian Diary typescript, 1933 (Box 14)
          Some carbon copy. With autograph notations.
      - In Praise of Poetry drafts, clippings, and notes (Box 14)
      - Inspiration and Rhythm: The New Rhythmic Drama; Art and Conduct typescripts, ca. 1927-1936 (Box 15)
        Includes autograph revisions. Earlier manuscript of essays that appeared in Spoken in Quiet.
      - Is There a Spiritual Atom? typescript, ca. 1945 (Box 15)
        Carbon copy with autograph revisions.
      - Letters to Niphoessa typescript, 1907-1933 (Box 15)
        Includes holograph revisions.
      - Milestones towards Journey's End typescript, ca. 1929 (Box 15)
      - Pereunt et Imputanur; Being My Contribution to the Bill typescript, 1906-1918 (Box 15)
        By E. Q. Includes holograph revisions.
      - "Plays", 1917-1945 (Box 15)
      - Recollections of Rupert Brooke
        - Correspondence with Arther String, Sir Edward Marsh, and Geoffrey Keynes, 1947-1952; 7 folders (Box 15)
        - Recollections of Rupert Brooke manuscripts
          - Recollections of Rupert Brooke: author's working copy, undated (Box 15)
          - Recollections of Rupert Brooke typescript, undated (Box 15)
          - Recollections of Rupert Brooke proof, ca. 1927 (Box 15)
        - Recollections of Rupert Brooke galleys and related correspondence, 1927-1928; 3 folders (Box 15)
        - Recollections of Rupert Brooke galleys, ca. 1927-1928 (Oversize 1)
      - Road from Delavan typescript and books, 1947 and undated (Box 15)
        Inscribed 1947. Includes a dealer description of this title and "B's copy" of Tomorrow's Sun.
      - Spoken in Quiet
        - Spoken in Quiet transcript, 1933 (Box 15)
          Includes autograph revisions "Excluded...from the prose volume of the same name".
        - Volume I: Bare Boards: Selected Prose, 1913-1927 typescript, 1934 (Box 15)
        - Vol. I: Bare Boards: Selected Prose, 1913-1927 typescript (Box 15)
          Carbon copy with typescript revisions and autograph notations.
      - Travel notes, 1900-1901 (Box 15)
      - Tunisian Treasure Trove typescript, 1931 (Box 15)
        Includes autograph corrections.
      - Without Comment working copy and reader's report, 1951-1952 (Box 15)
      - Yseult of Ireland criticism (Box 15)
      - Miscellaneous Essays typescript and autograph, 1933 and undated (Box 15)
    - Maurice Browne poetry
      - Delavan
        - Delavan manuscript (Box 15)
        - "Road from Delavan" typescript (Box 15)
        - Delavan typescript (Box 15)
          Carbon copy with autograph revisions and correspondence.
        - Delavan typescript (Box 15)
          Carbon copy with autograph revisions. Title page inscribed with Ellen Van Volkenburg's New York address and Maurice Browne's London address.
        - Romantic Sonata (1912-1942) typescript, ca. 1943 (Box 15)
          Alternate title for Delavan.
      - Early poems typescript (Box 15)
      - "Further Poems Written in Old Age" manuscript, 1948-1955 (Box 15)
      - In Time of War typescript (Box 15)
        Carbon copy with autograph revisions. Title page inscribed in Greek.
      - "Manuscripts of Poetry" manuscripts and fragments (Box 15)
      - Moonshine: A Little Book of Rhymes for Children from Six to Sixty typescript (Box 15)
      - "On My Thirtieth Birthday", 1910 (Box 15)
        Removed from Maurice Browne's letters to his mother.
      - Passer-By typescript (Box 15)
      - Poems returned from Arthur Ficke (Box 15)
        Items sent to Arthur Ficke and later returned to Browne with Ficke's letters.
      - "Swan-Song" and "Rock and Pool", 1943-1944 (Box 15)
      - Poetry fragments and discards, 1917-1941 (Box 15)
      - "Virgin" (Box 15)
    - Maurice Browne poetry and prose
      - Obita Dicta, 1918
        - Obita Dicta cover and notes, ca. 1954 (Box 15)
        - Obita Dicta prose, 1901-1910 (Box 15)
        - Obita Dicta open letters and replies (Box 15)
        - Obita Dicta (Box 15)
        - The Sex, 1901-1903 (Box 15)
          Serial edited by Maurice Browne.
        - Darjiling Cricket Reports, etc., 1904-1905 (Box 15)
          Note in Maurice Browne's hand: "authorship in some cases not Maurice Browne's, in many cases doubtful".
      - "Poems excluded from vols. 1-4 / by Maurice Browne / Together with Notes for my Executors / etc.", 1946 (Box 15)
      - Poems notebook, 1910; 1 Volumes (Box 15)
        Blank book given to Maurice Browne by Ellen Van Volkenburg in 1910.
      - Sundry Mss. volume, 1927, 1936
        Ellen Van Volkenburg's copy. Includes poetry and prose. Bound in 1927, with additions dated 1936.
        - A Prologue to Job (Box 16)
        - Epithalamios, 1903-1905 (Box 16)
        - In Time of War (Box 16)
        - Lyrical Poems, 1911; 3 Volumes (Box 16)
        - Songs of Exile (Box 16)
        - Spoken in Quiet (Box 16)
          Italian diary.
        - Poems, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Maurice Browne miscellaneous writings
      - "A Note on Poetic Truth" (Box 16)
      - "Ananda Kantish Coomaraswamy", undated (Box 16)
      - Californian Theatre article (Box 16)
      - The Beginnings of the "Little Theatre Movement" in America (Box 16)
      - A Doll's House review (Box 16)
        Critical review, apparently unpublished, of Dartington Hall production of Ibsen's A Doll's House.